Most Word documents are combined of text.
However, there are occasions where you
may wish to enhance the appearance of the
document, make it look more informative
or more eye catching, and you can do that
by inserting tables, charts and images.
In this short video, I'm going to insert
an image and a chart just to display
information in a different way, and to
personalise the letter to the business.
So the first thing I'll do, I'm going
to insert the company logo above the
address at the top of the letter.
So what I need to do, I need to
ensure that the cursor is blinking,
where I wish to insert the image.
A good point to remember is wherever
your cursor is blinking, that is
where it will import the information
or place the information that
you're putting into the document.
So I've got that blinking
just above the address.
I will go to the insert tab,
I'll select, it's a picture
and it's a picture from file.
So it's a picture that I
have saved on the computer.
So I'll select that and I'll
save that into my WP2 folder.
So I can just click on the
balloon image and that will insert
the image into the document.
Now, as you can see, the image
is quite large and I can reduce
the size of it by clicking on
the little squares at the corner.
And I will do that by the
corner one, because that will
keep the aspect ratio correct.
If I reduced it in size using the side
it will compress the image exactly
the same if I did it via the bottom.
So I use the corner and that shrinks the
image and keeps the aspect ratio correct.
So once I'm satisfied
and I'm happy with that.
So then I've inserted the image.
So I'm happy with that.
I could lower the transparency.
I could do some artistic effects.
There's various things you could
do once the image is in there.
And for this one, I'm just going to
lower the transparency a little, just
so it isn't standing out as much.
So that's the logo now entered.
So the next thing I'm going to do is I'm
going to import a chart just to display
the sales information for the team.
And again, I'll place the cursor
where I want to insert the chart.
And I have the chart already set up in
an Excel spreadsheet, and I've created
the chart using the sales information.
You will learn more about
this in the spreadsheet unit.
So what I need to do is I'm just
going to highlight the chart.
And as you can see, as soon as I've
highlighted it it's telling me where
it's drawing the information from.
So I'll highlight that and
I'll use the Command and C,
which has now copied the chart.
And if I place my cursor
there and then Command and V.
It will place the chart into the letter.
Good thing to remember is that it's
still linked to the actual information.
Now there are the paste options at
the bottom where I can paste as a
picture but as you can see, I've
got Chart Linked to the Excel data.
And the most important thing about
that is that means that if I change the
information in the Excel spreadsheet, it
would update it within the actual chart.